Guide to the Adelaide Bean Papers TAM.756
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Adelaide Bean Papers
1921-1999
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Bean, Adelaide
Frank, Kate
TAM.756
18.5 linear feet in 34 manuscript boxes, 1 small flat box, 1 oversize flat box, 1 record carton, and 3 folders in a shared box
48 sound tape reels
1 videocassettes (vhs)
1 videocassettes (vhs-c)
38 audiocassettes
Adelaide Bean was an actress, a journalist, and a member of the Communist Party of the United States of America (CPUSA). The Adelaide Bean Papers consist of working papers, correspondence, drafts, publications, ephemera, audio reels, and audiocassettes created and collected by Bean documenting her personal and political life, as well as her career in theater and journalism.
Scope and Contents
The Adelaide Bean Papers consist of materials created and collected by Bean documenting her personal, political, and professional life.
Series I. Personal Files, consists of materials that document Bean's personal life, including correspondence with friends and family, greeting cards, and photographs.
Series II. Theatrical Work, documents Bean's career as an actress and playwright, including programs, playbills, play manuscripts, musical scores, newspaper clippings of reviews of productions, correspondence and working papers, and documentation of Bean's involvement in labor unions and associations representing working performers. It also includes works by some of her colleagues, including Barrie Stavis, Marc Blitzstein, and Norman Curtis, many with notes and revisions from Bean.
Series III. Journalism, documents Bean's career as a journalist and editor. These materials are from her early work as a market researcher, her work as co-editor of Labor Today from 1971-1974, and her tenure as arts editor of The People's Daily World from the late 1970s to 1980s. It also includes the works of her journalist, writer, and poet colleagues, including Meridel Le Sueur, Walter Lowenfels, and Art Shields. Much of this work is related to the Communist Party and labor issues in subject matter.
Series IV. Subject Files, includes materials collected by Bean on a variety of topics includes materials that Bean collected on a variety of topics related to labor organizing, theater, and communism.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in four series:
Series I. Personal Files, consists of materials that document Bean's personal life. This series is arranged chronologically.
Series II. Theatrical Work, documents Bean's career as an actress and playwright. This series is arranged chronologically.
Series III. Journalism, documents Bean's career as a journalist and editor. This series is arranged chronologically.
Series IV. Subject Files, includes materials that Bean collected on a variety of topics related to labor organizing, theater, and communism. This series is arranged alphabetically.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Kate Frank, Adelaide Bean's daughter, in October 2018; the accession number associated with this gift is 2018.125.
Biographical Note
Adelaide Bean was an actress, a journalist, and a member of the Communist Party of the United States of America (CPUSA).
Bean grew up in Connecticut, in a small town between Hartford and New Britain. Her mother was a musician and her father was a business executive. She studied music and voice at the Oxford School in Hartford and graduated in 1928. At 16, she took on her first theatrical role playing piano for the traveling Jitney Players. By 18, she taught music at a private school in Sarasota, Florida. After two years of teaching, she decided to move to New York to focus on acting.
Adelaide Bean's first marriage was in 1934 to Richard Summey, who she later divorced. She had two children, Kate and Jan.
Bean's first big acting break in New York was a role in the original Broadway production of The Late Christopher Bean. She also described this show as the beginning of her political consciousness. The next year she acted in Eugene O'Neill's Ah, Wilderness and worked as Herman Shumlin's assistant on the original Broadway production of The Children's Hour. Shortly after, Bean produced the original Broadway production of Let Freedom Ring by Albert Barne, which depicted textile strikes in the South.
In 1935-1936, during the Spanish Civil War, Bean produced a play about Spain titled Who Fights This Battle with Joseph Losey as director and Kenneth White as writer. It was written and produced in ten days with 60 actors, at least 50 of which were earning a living through the Works Progress Administration's Federal Theatre Project. There were only three performances. She described the play as one of her first political memories.
From Who Fights This Battle came the Theatre Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy, which eventually turned into the Theater Arts Committee (TAC). Adelaide Bean was TAC's executive secretary, and she produced the TAC Cabaret in 1938, which featured political works such as Joe Hill, Peat Bog Soldiers, and Strange Fruit. Performances took place at the Firehouse Theater, and proceeds of the Cabaret helped war relief in Spain. The TAC Cabaret was also influential in the creation of the Actors Front to Win the War, spurred on by Charlie Chaplin.
Bean joined the Communist Party in March of 1936, after her and many of her colleagues became involved in the rank and file movement of the Actors' Equity Association.
In 1943, Adelaide Bean married Robert Caille-Reed. Robert was also an actor and Communist Party member, and he was the organizer of the Cultural Section of the Party, which consisted of workers in music, theater, radio, and film.
During World War II, Bean was involved in Russian War Relief, which sent money, clothing, food, and medical supplies to the Soviet Union. She was also active in civic campaigns such as the Musicians Emergency Fund Relief and Stop Censorship.
After World War II ended, Adelaide Bean attended the General Electric strike in Schenectady with Robert and their children. Robert was the organizer of the strike. Actor Zero Mostel also attended the strike, where he announced that he would refuse the airing of a General Electric commercial that he was in.
Bean described feeling optimistic that the world may emerge victorious against fascism after WWII. Living in New York, she continued working on Stop Censorship, and on a petition to the United Nations to end genocide. She and Robert were also involved in the struggle and aftermath of the riots at Paul Robeson's Peekskill concert.
In the early 1950s, Adelaide's theater and television acting career was in full swing. She performed in many New York theaters, including the Pulitzer Prize Playhouse, Celanese Theater, Hallmark Hall of Fame, Firehouse Theater, and others. She portrayed Widda Machree in the world premiere of Sean O'Casey's Time to Go.
In 1953, Bean was blacklisted from the television industry. Another actor had cleared himself by saying that she tried to recruit him to the Communist Party. She moved to Chicago and worked odd jobs to make a living, including working at a small electrical parts shop, conducting interviews for market research, giving private music lessons, and acting in educational films for Encyclopedia Brittanica. During this time, she worked with Barrie Stavis on his play Joe Hill. She was also an acting member of the Resident Company of the Cherry County Playhouse in Traverse City, Michigan during the 1957 summer season.
In the early 1960s, Adelaide Bean wrote and produced Bless the Child, which premiered at Karamu Theatre in 1963. It was co-authored by Bernice Blohm and directed by Reuben Silver, with music by Irma Jurist. The play centers a group of women workers at a Chicago electrical parts factory.
Bean stayed in Chicago for 20 years, and it was there that her career in journalism began. She was co-editor of Labor Today from 1971-1974. Some of her volunteer work from this era includes her role as co-chair of the Midwest Artists for Peace Drama Committee, as well as her work on the Artists United Paul Robeson committee in the late 1960s.
In 1974, Communist Party chairman Gus Hall asked Bean to be the arts editor for the Communist Party's newspaper, The People's Daily World. She accepted his invitation and moved back to New York City, where she wrote for the World into the late 1980s and remained active in labor organizing and the Communist Party. Adelaide Bean passed away in 1999.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Some audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Appraisal
In 2021, two record cartons were deaccessioned from the collection. The boxes contained published books, published manuscripts, and personal financial and legal documents.
Hollywood blacklist.; Blacklisting of entertainers.; Actors -- Labor unions -- United States; Communism -- United States -- 20th century; Women and communism -- United States -- History -- 20th century.; Theater -- Political aspects.; Socialism and theater.; Communism and culture -- United States.; Journalism, Communist -- United States.; Labor journalism -- New York (State) -- New York.; Art -- Censorship -- United States.; Frank, Kate; Communist Party of the United States of America; SAG-AFTRA (Organization); Actors' Equity Association
- Series I. Personal Files, 1921-1999
  Scope and Contents
  Series I. Personal Files, consists of materials that document Bean's personal life, including correspondence with friends and family, greeting cards, and photographs.
  - Correspondence with Family, 1921-1956 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Oxford School - Playbills and Event Programs, 1925-1930 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence with Family, 1925-1935 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence with Family, 1928-1932 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Oxford School - "Who Is That Oxford Girl?", circa 1928 - 1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence with Family, 1933-1957 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Adelaide Bean and Richard Summey's Wedding - Newspaper Clippings, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence from Robert Caille-Reed to Adelaide Bean, 1935-1945 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Robert Caille-Reed - Correspondence and Documents, 1937-1946 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Unlabeled Photographs, circa 1940-1990 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Russian War Relief Volunteer Efforts, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Adelaide Bean and Robert Caille's Marriage Certificate, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Robert Caille-Reed - Notes and Drawings, circa 1940-1950 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Robert Caille-Reed - Course Outlines and Teaching Notes, circa 1945-1950 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Robert Caille-Reed - Public Speaking Class, circa 1945-1950 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Robert Caille-Reed on Hollywood and Censorship, 1947-1948 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Robert Caille-Reed - Notes on the Communist Party Cultural Division, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Robert Caille-Reed - Wallace Campaign, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Robert Caille-Reed on the Taft-Hartley Act, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Robert Caille-Reed's Death - Newspaper Tributes, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Robert Caille-Reed's Death - Sympathy Correspondence, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Robert Caille-Reed - Memorial Service Program, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence from Kate and Jan's Childhood Education, circa 1950-1960 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - New York Contacts, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Barrie Stavis - Correspondence, 1953-1964 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Barrie Stavis - Correspondence, 1953-1972 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Memories of Chicago - Correspondence, receipts, pocketbook, 1954-1974 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence with Kate, circa 1960-1965 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Meridel Le Sueur - Correspondence, 1960-1990 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence with Family, 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Barrie Stavis - Correspondence, 1964-1978 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Memorial Booklet for Adelaide Bean Sr., 1967 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence with Friends, 1967-1995 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Bob Hollowwa - Correspondence, 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Transcripts of Adelaide Bean's Interviews with Vivian McGuckin-Raineri and John Kailin, 1974-1985 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Birthday Cards and Correspondence from Family and Friends, 1974-1991 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - John Kailin - Correspondence, 1974-1995 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Pete Seeger - Correspondence, 1976-1984 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Poetry Collected by Adelaide, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Catherine Sanford, Victoria Petrilli, and Michael Petrilli - Correspondence and drafts, 1977-1984 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Mark Pawlak - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Photograph of Adelaide Bean, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Meridel Le Sueur's Birthday, February 23, 1980 (Box 35, Audiocassette 756_049)
  - Photographs from Adelaide Bean's Birthday Party, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Photographs labelled "New York in the 80's" and "Victoria Petrilli", circa 1980s (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Frederick Eaton's Memorial Service and Photos, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence that Accompanied Audio Reel 756_064, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Adelaide Bean NYC: Interview by Vivian Raineri, May 23, 1984 (Box 35, Audiocassette 756_050, 756_051)
  - Certificate of Appreciation for Adelaide Bean from the Communist Party of the United States of America (CPUSA), 1986 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence and Photographs with Friends, 1986-1993 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Peggy Lipschutz - Correspondence, Event Flyers, Photograph, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Richard Inglis, Jr. - Correspondence and Family Chart, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Inventory of Adelaide Bean's Files, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Conrad Komorowski - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Address Books, 1990-1995 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Greeting Cards from Friends and Family, 1990-1996 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Michael Komorowski - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Address Directory and Pocket Calendar, 1991-1997 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Ronn Yedidia and Fiona Grant - Correspondence and Concert Programs, 1994-1996 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Cards from Adelaide Bean's Hospital Stay, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Pocketbook and Photograph, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Kate Frank's interview with Ruthann Rebecca about McCarthy era memories, October, 1997 (Box 35, Audiocassette 756_053)
  - "Family's Experience" by Kate Frank, May 15, 1998 (Box 35, Vhs 756_079)
  - Letter from Kate Frank to Nursing Home after Adelaide Bean's Death, circa 1999 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Guestbook for Adelaide Bean's Memorial Celebration, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Adelaide Bean, Undated (Box 35, Audiocassette 756_052)
  - Notes on Adelaide Bean's Family History, Undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Notes that Accompanied Audio Reels, Undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Note that Accompanied Audio Reel 756_065, Undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Photographs "to look at with Peg Lipschutz", Undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Photographs of Robert Caille-Reed with Notes, Undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Rolodex Card Catalog, Undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Series II. Theatrical Work, 1923-1997
  Series II. Theatrical Work, documents Bean's career as an actress and playwright, including programs, playbills, play manuscripts, musical scores, newspaper clippings of reviews of productions, correspondence and working papers, and documentation of Bean's involvement in labor unions and associations representing working performers. It also includes works by some of her colleagues, including Barrie Stavis, Marc Blitzstein, and Norman Curtis, many with notes and revisions from Bean.
  - Industrial Workers of the World Songs and other Labor Arts, 1923-1985 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Mailing Lists for Activist Organizations, circa 1930-1950 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Adelaide Bean's Early Acting Career - Playbills, 1931-1948 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Fan Drawing of Adelaide in The Late Christopher Bean, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Adelaide Bean's Early Acting Career - Newspaper Clippings, 1932-1935 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - The Children's Hour Manuscript Draft, circa 1935 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Adelaide Bean worked as assistant producer on the original Broadway production of The Children's Hour in 1935.
  - Let Freedom Ring, Produced by Adelaide Bean, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Associated Actors and Artistes of America - 4 A's Union, 1935-1949 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Who Fights This Battle? by Kenneth White, Produced by Adelaide Bean - Flyer, circa 1935-1936 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Who Fights This Battle? by Kenneth White, Produced by Adelaide Bean - Manuscripts, Drafts, and Correspondence, 1936-1996 (Box 6, Folder 10, 11, 12, 13)
  - Theatre Committee for Aid to Spanish Democracy - Theatre People's Rally, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Theatre Arts Committee (TAC), 1937-1940 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Theatre Arts Committee (TAC) - Activities and Meeting Minutes, 1937-1940 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Theatre Organizing Notes and Working Papers, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Theatre Arts Committee Cabaret, 1938-1939 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Marc Blitzstein - Playbills, Musical Scores, Newspaper Clippings, 1939-1984 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Meridel Le Sueur - Profiles, Works, Event Programs, 1939-1990 (Box 7, Folder 4, 5)
  - Why Do You Stand There in the Rain? Musical Score by Woody Guthrie, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Barrie Stavis - Play Manuscripts and Drafts, circa 1940-1970 (Box 7, Folder 7, 8, 9, 10, Box 8, Folder 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, Box 9, Box 10)
    Includes drafts and final versions of the following plays, many with notes and annotations from Adelaide Bean:
    27 Billion Dollars, 1940; Banners of Steel, 1960-1962; Coat of Many Colors, 1963; The House of Shadows, n.d.; Joe Hill, n.d.; Lamp at Midnight, n.d.; The Man Who Never Died, 1973; Sun and I, 1946; Washington, n.d.
  - Play Manuscripts and Drafts - Various Authors, circa 1940-1991 (Box 10, Folder 8, 9, Box 11, Folder 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, Box 12, Folder 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7)
    Includes drafts and final manuscripts of the following plays:
    Amazing Grace by Studs Terkel, 1959; Bed Time Story by Sam Moore, n.d.; Declaration by Janet and Philip Stevenson, 1940; Drop Hammer by Emanuel Fried, 1977; Faust, unattributed, n.d.; In Praise of Paper Power by Charles Friedman, n.d.; Love and the Census Taker by Albert Bein, n.d.; The Oregon Trail #623 film script by John Barnes and Benton Leibson, 1955; Paul Robeson in Concert by Phillip Hayes Dean, n.d.; Sandhog by Earl Robinson and Waldo Salt, 1954; Spoken Songs by Walter Lowenfels and Norman Curtis, n.d.; They Shall be Heard by Norman Rosten, n.d.; This is My Friend film script by Allegro Film Productions, Inc., 1956; Trial by Error by John Speeking, 1982; Mitchell Berenson Play, n.d.; Untitled manuscripts by Noble, n.d.; Untitled and unattributed manuscript, n.d.; Untitled and unattributed manuscript, 1991.
  - Artist's Front to Win the War, 1942-1943 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Lunchtime Follies, 1942-1943 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - People's Songs Bulletin, 1945 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - American-Soviet Music Review, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - The American National Theater and Academy, 1946-1949 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Stop Censorship, 1947 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Resolution on the United States Office of Repertory Theatres, 1947-1949 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Stop Censorship - Flyer and Newspaper Clippings, 1947-1986 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Stop Censorship Signature Cards, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Federal Subsidy of the Arts, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Stop Censorship - Working Papers, 1948-1951 (Box 13, Folder 10, 11, 12)
  - Adelaide's Work and Activism in Chicago - Correspondence, Working Papers, 1948-1952 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Actors' Equity Association - Anti-Blacklist Resolution, 1948-1976 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Paul Robeson - Peekskill Riots Newspaper Clippings, 1949 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - The Margaret Webster Shakespeare Company, 1949 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Theatre Committee to Save the Life of Walter Lee Irvin, 1949 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - They Shall Not Die by John Wexley, 1949 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Paul Robeson - Peekskill Riots and Hollywood Eagle Concert, 1949 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Paul Robeson - Peekskill Riots Newspaper Clippings, 1949 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - American Federation of Radio Artists + Television Authority Merger (AFTRA), 1949-1951 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Bill Marshall - Actors' Equity Association Correspondence, 1950 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Adelaide Bean's 1951 Television Appearances, 1950-1951 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Adelaide Bean's Theater and Television Roles, 1951-1957 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Adelaide Bean's Actors' Equity Association Member Card, 1952 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Notes on the Need for One Big Union of Theatrical Performers, circa 1952 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Paul Robeson - Newspaper Profiles, 1952-1976 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - American Federation of Television and Radio Artists (AFTRA), AFL-CIO, 1952-1986 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Barrie Stavis - Joe Hill Research, 1953 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - The World of Sholom Aleichem Production Contract Draft, 1953 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Barrie Stavis - Joe Hill Publicity, 1953-1954 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Barrie Stavis - Joe Hill Playbills and Press, 1953-1974 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Paul Robeson - Concert Programs, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Paul Robeson - Passport Case, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Cherry County Playhouse 1957 Season - Feature in the Record Eagle (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Adelaide Bean's Class at the Lenhoff School of Music and Dance, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Norman Curtis - Correspondence, Event Programs, Press, 1959-1971 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Bless the Child by Bernice Blohm and Adelaide Bean - Manuscripts and Drafts, circa 1960-1963 (Box 15, Folder 6, 7, 8)
  - Sonata for Flute and Piano: Norman Curtis and Harvey Sollberger, June, 1961 (Box 37, Reel 756_047)
    A note on the original box said, "To Adelaide with love - Norman, June 1961"
  - Committee for the Employment of Negro Performers, 1961-1962 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Barrie Stavis - Drafts, The Sun and I and The Coat of Many Colors, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Barrie Stavis - Banners of Steel Playbills and Press, 1963-1965 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Bless the Child Premiere - Playbills and Press, 1963-1968 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Bless the Child Reviews, 1963-1968 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Actors' Equity Association - Rank and File Activities, 1963-1979 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Bless the Child Production Contract, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Bless the Child Correspondence with Bernice Diskin, Irma Jurist, Barrie Stavis, and others, 1964-1968 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Barrie Stavis - Lamp at Midnight Playbills and Press, 1965-1969 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Barrie Stavis - Playbills and Press, 1966-1986 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Barrie Stavis - Correspondence and drafts, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Midwest Artists for Peace - Newspaper Clippings, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Midwest Artists for Peace - Protests Against the Vietnam War, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Tyrone Guthrie - Playbills, 1967-1968 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Karamu Theatre - Playbills, Calls for Auditions, Press, 1967-1968 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Barrie Stavis - Harpers Ferry Playbills and Press, circa 1967-1970 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Actors' Equity Association Activities, 1967-1989 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Black Theater in Chicago, 1968-1969 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Artists United - Paul Robeson Week, 1969-1970 (Box 17, Folder 3, 4)
  - Coalition for United Community Action, Chicago, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 5)